Timothy Reznichenko

Senior Frontend Engineer / Senior Full Stack Engineer

Experienced engineer with 7+ years of Typescript/Javascript Full Stack expertise and 3 years as a Team Lead. Spearheaded a team of more than 20 engineers, collaborating with business partners to launch the largest Italian ad platform. Delivered projects for clients, such as FIAT, Mastercard, and Netflix.

Experience

Co-Founder & Lead Hands-on

Lambda Bird sp. z o.o. - Web Development Agency

Feb 2020 - Present I Warsaw, Poland I 3 years

- Collaborated with clients to identify their needs, designed custom solutions, executed projects within scope and budget, resulting in a 95% satisfaction.
- Utilized expertise of React, Node.js, GraphQL and Solidity to develop MVPs for clients, resulting in successful fundraising of over \$100k for them.
- Developed dashboards and bots for on-chain analytics and MEV, using Dune, Graph Protocol and DefiLlama.

Volunteer Software Engineer

IT Army of Ukraine

24 Feb 2022 - Mar 2023 | Remote (Ukraine) | 1 year

Software Engineering Team Lead

Mint.ai - the largest Italian Ad Automation platform, has raised €50 million Feb 2019 – Feb 2022 | Remote (Milan, Italy) | 3 years

- Spearheaded a remote team of 20+ full stack engineers, set team goals, hosted 1-1's and conducted more than 100 technical interviews.
- Led requirements analysis, design, dev and test management. Cut release prep time by 80% via optimised code reviews and tech debt reduction.
- Implemented a microfrontend architecture, exceeding performance goals by 50% and productivity by 30% for 50+ cross-functional team members.
- Launched 4 new applications that earned a combined €3M in revenue.

Founder & Lead Full Stack Developer

 $\underline{\text{Local Relayer (prev. Instex)}} - \text{Open-source Decentralized Exchange}$ Feb 2018 – Jan 2019 | Kyiv, Ukraine | 1 year

- Led a team of 3 engineers in developing a Node.js API, that supported 1000+ concurrent trades, resulting in a 75% increase in trade volumes.
- Mentored junior engineers in best practices for code quality, git, and testing, resulting in a 30% decrease in bugs and a 40% increase in test coverage.
- Implemented scalable and fault-tolerant AWS infrastructure, resulting in a 70% reduction in infrastructure costs and a 20% increase in uptime.

Front End Javascript Engineer

<u>BitFit</u> — Asset management system used by Netflix and Hulu Oct 2016 – Jan 2018 | Remote (San Francisco, USA) | 1 year 4

- Rewrote the platform from Backbone to React & TS resulting in a 60% increase in page loading speed and a 30% increase in user engagement.
- · Engineered real-time customizable dashboards with d3.js and WebSocket.
- · Coded an offline React Native app that increased props issuance by 40%.

Junior Front End Engineer

ST manage - Web Entertainment Studio (out of business)

Sep 2015 - Oct 2016 | Kyiv, Ukraine | 1 year 2 months

· Developed web apps and HTML5 games with custom React UI Kit.

Contacts

Wroclaw, Poland Open to relocation



<u>Telegram</u>

tim.reznich@gmail.com

Linkedin

Github

Skills

- Agile, LeSS, SAFe, Scrum, Jira, Disciplined Agile, ToC.
- Tech leadership, Mentorship, Async communication.
- Typescript, React, Redux, Next, Apollo, D3.js, Three.js
- Node.js (Fastify, Koa, Express), Nest.js, Graphql.
- Solidity, Hardhat, Foundry, Ethers.js, web3.js, Truffle.
- Jest, Mocha, React Testing Library, Selenium, Cypress.
- PostgreSQL, Mongodb, MySQL, Redis, RabbitMQ.
- Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, GitFlow, CI/CD, Terraform.
- · UX/UI design, Figma, Sketch.
- CSS (PostCSS, Sass, Less), HTML, Tailwind, MUI, Ant.

Education

 National University of Kyiv-Mohyla Academy
 Marketing and Management 2013-2017

Achievements

- EthOnline2022 Hackathon
 Won 3 pool prizes
- Deep Learning Specialization
 Coursera certificate
 Issued Oct 2018
- Better Async with Redux Saga Speaker at React Kyiv Meetup Jul 2018

Languages

• English: Fluent (C1)

· Ukrainian: Native (C2)